Carson Bruce Senior Software Engineer

Montreal, QC Canada • carson.bruce@gmail.com • +1 (438) 529 4567 linkedin.com/in/carsonbruce

INTRODUCTION

I am a seasoned software engineer with more than 13 years of experience. Throughout my career, I have successfully navigated the entire software development lifecycle, from concept to deployment. My diverse experience has equipped me with valuable problem-solving skills and a passion for continuous learning and collaboration with teams large and small. Known for my open-minded approaches, attentive listening, and promoting strong teamwork, I am committed to driving innovation and exceeding expectations in every role I undertake.

EXPERIENCE

STAY22 TECHNOLOGIES INC

Sept 2024 - Present

Senior Full Stack Developer

- Led delivery of a new design system and front-end architecture serving 2,000+ daily users.
- Mentored junior developers, accelerating growth in both technical and soft skills.
- Built internal tooling, saving up to 12 developer hours per month.
- Promoted best practices and set technical direction through presentations and design documentation.
- Drove cultural shift to test automation, accelerating delivery from weekly to continuous across two projects.
- Integrated AI tools into developer workflows, boosting code quality and team productivity.

THE BLACK BELTS Apr 2024 - Sept 2024

Senior Software Engineer

- Led API and microservice design to enable customer adoption of new Open Banking standards.
- Led backend development for 3 of NZ's top 5 banks, driving multi-million revenue and serving 1M+ users.
- Shared technical knowledge with the product team through presentations, code reviews, and documentation.
- Subject matter expert in Open Banking, influencing standards through monthly committee feedback.
- Worked directly with customers listening to feedback and designing proposals for new features.

FORSYTH BARR Dec 2022 - Feb 2024

Senior Software Engineer

- Led backend development of AWS serverless APIs (Python/TypeScript) managing \$1M+ in customer funds.
- Core contributor of Javascript, Typescript and Python SDKs development and releases.
- Responsible for design and development of Identity and Access Control systems using AWS products including IAM, Lambda, DynamoDB, AppSync.
- Trusted as part of the hiring team, running technical interviews with candidates and hiring 5 new members.
- Created internal tooling used across the company to support common queries and reports.

TROVE NZ Feb 2022 - Nov 2022

Senior Full Stack Developer

- Championed a load testing framework improving confidence of the leadership team to launch the product.
- Became proficient in Python within 3 months, contributing to code reviews and feature design.
- Built shared libraries and release strategies, enabling 4 internal web applications.
- Collaborated with the data team to deliver improvements to reliability of data and performance of the pipeline.
- Saved \$10,000+ monthly hosting costs through service refactoring and consolidation.

MIDDLEWARE NZ Mar 2019 - Feb 2022

Senior Developer

- Developed, tested, and deployed critical apps for banking, COVID ID, and healthcare serving 1M+ users.
- Encouraged a culture of test automation by implementing and socializing testing frameworks across teams.
- Proved reliability by managing 6+ client projects concurrently.
- Received 4 promotions over a short period proving myself as a valued and trusted team member.
- Researched and implemented complex standards including OAuth, OIDC, FHIR, 3-D Secure, Open Banking.

PROPERLY INC Nov 2017 - Mar 2019

Full Stack Developer

- Front-end technical lead managing 2 engineers and a web app with 1,000+ daily active users.
- Embedded test automation practices, reducing production monitoring issues.

- Enhanced developer experience with branch-based deployments and environment configs.
- Supported \$12M Series A by providing user metrics for due diligence.
- Facilitated alignment between front-end, design, research, content, and product teams.
- Decoupled front-end API deployment, boosting performance, stability, and user experience.

SOLNET SOLUTIONS

Software Engineer

- Aug 2012 Nov 2017
- Delivered 30+ client projects across diverse domains and tech stacks, driving \$5M+ in revenue.
- Led on-time, on-budget solution still in use after 10 years and reused in two later projects.
- Supported 60+ developers and testers by improving CI pipelines and shared libraries.
- Provided training and mentorship in front-end skills through presentations, code reviews, and team embedding.

PROJECTS

HUB

Stay22

Stay22's partner-facing platform, delivering insights and trend-driven recommendations to drive growth.

OPEN BANKING PLATFORM

Glueware

An accelerator to simplify a bank's journey to production-ready Open Banking, providing secure, ready-to-use, standards compliant APIs.

FINTECH PLATFORM

Forsyth Barr

A platform to power the first guided investment app in NZ. This platform fortified Forsyth Barr's technology capabilities by supporting multiple products.

EDUCATION

VICTORIA UNIVERSITY OF WELLINGTON

Bachelor of Engineering with First Class Honors, Majoring in Software Engineering.

REFERENCES

Contact details will be provided on request.

- SASHA Head of Engineering at Stay22
- SWITHIN Head of Integration at Middleware NZ
- **JARED** Head of Engineering at Forsyth Barr
- JAMES Financial Engineering Team Lead at Trove
- NAMI Principle Engineer at Solnet
- RAFAEL CTO of Properly

SKILLS

- Languages & Frameworks: Javascript, Typescript, Python, C#, Java, GraphQL, OAuth, OIDC, Express, .NET, NextJS, React, Angular, Vue, K6, RxJS
- **DevOps:** Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Helm, Google Cloudbuild, NPM, GitHub Actions, Jenkins
- Cloud: AWS (Lambda, DynamoDB, Route 53, S3, Event Bridge, IAM, Appsync, SQS, SES, CloudFront), Google Cloud Platform (Functions, Kubernetes Engine, App Engine, CloudBuild), Azure (AD B2C).
- Databases: MongoDB, DynamoDB, Redis, PostgreSQL, ElasticSearch, Kibana, Snowflake
- Software Development: Agile Methodologies, Continuous Integration, RESTful API Design, Test-Driven
 Development, Microservices Architecture, Serverless Architecture, Event Driven Architecture, In Office / Hybrid /
 Remote Working